Guide to the Stewart O'Nan papers, 1987-2009.
O'Nan, Stewart papers
- Series XXII. Miscellaneous/ Works by Other Authors
  - Subseries XXII b. Miscellaneous
    - Reid Mariani "Monica Miles, Aunt Edith and the Circus Fire" (Box 60)
    - Brett Savory "In and Down" (Box 60)
    - Paul Cody "Night Lights" (Box 60)
    - Writer's Harvest 3 edited by Tobias Wolff, 2000 (Box 60)
    - The Top Ten edited by J. Peder Zane, 2007 (Box 60)
    - Various literary magazines (Box 60)
    - Short Fiction by 33 Writers edited by Mark Winegardner (Box 60)
    - OK Best: A Collection of Short Stories edited by Kelly Ross Jump and Libby Price, 1997 (Box 60)
    - Literary conferences correspondence, foreign press essays and reviews (Box 60)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 55)
    - Miscellaneous Literary review magazines (Box 62)
  - Subseries XXII c. Books on Writing
    - Telling True Stories edited by Mark Kramer and Wendy Call (Box 60)
    - Novel and Short Story Writer's Market edited by Anne Bowling (Box 60)
    - The Last Pentacle of the Sun edited by MW Anderson and Brett Savory, signed, 2004 (Box 62)
    - The 54th national Book Awards ceremony booklet, 2003 (Box 61)
- Series XXIII. General Correspondence
  - A, 2004 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    Ainsworth, Arvin
  - Steve Almond, 2001-2002 (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - A. Manette Ansay, 2000-2006 (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - Rilla Askew, 1998-1999 (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Ba-Bi, 1998-2002 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    Bacon, Baggot, Bannon, Baran, Bass, Baxter, Beattie, Bell, Beller, Bernstein, Bettendorf, Bill
  - Bi-Bo, 1998-2006 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    Blackwell, Borchardt, Boston Red Sox, Braver, Bryant, Buell, Buffalo
  - Blake Bailey, 2005-2006 (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - Frederick Busch, 1999-2004 (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - C, 1998-2005 (Box 57, Folder 9)
    Cahill, Canin, Carroll, Castiglione, Chapman, Chikes, Clark, Cochane, Coghlan, Cohen, Cole, Coleman, Coste
  - Annie Callan I, 1998 (Box 57, Folder 10)
  - Annie Callan II, 1999-2003 (Box 57, Folder 11)
  - Lori Marie Carlson, 2002 (Box 57, Folder 12)
  - Michael Casey, 1998-2005 (Box 57, Folder 13)
  - Charles Champlin, 1998 (Box 57, Folder 14)
  - Susan Choi, 1998-1999 (Box 57, Folder 15)
  - Paul Cody I, 1998-2004 (Box 57, Folder 16)
  - Paul Cody II, 2004-2006 (Box 57, Folder 17)
    Includes 2005 letter from S. O'Nan to Cornell University Search Committee; Pre-Blurb for "Finding Norman"
  - Alejandro Crawford, 1998 (Box 57, Folder 18)
  - D, 1998-2002 (Box 57, Folder 19)
    Datlow, Dax, Dell Publishers, Dent, Dueber
  - Adam Davies, 1999-2001 (Box 57, Folder 20)
  - Cathy Day, 2004 (Box 57, Folder 21)
  - Pamela Ditchoff, 1998-2006 (Box 57, Folder 22)
  - Doubleday, 1996 (Box 57, Folder 23)
  - Michael Downs, 2001-2004 (Box 57, Folder 24)
  - Peter Duvall, 2006 (Box 57, Folder 25)
  - E, 1999-2002 (Box 57, Folder 26)
    Ellison, Elwood, Etra, Eyre
  - Jennifer Egan, 1998-2006 (Box 57, Folder 27)
  - Andrew Ervin, 2001-2003 (Box 57, Folder 28)
  - Jeffrey Eugenides, 1998 (Box 57, Folder 29)
  - F, 1998-2004 (Box 57, Folder 30)
    Farrar Strauss Giroux, Fineberg, Forty Acres, Fromberg
  - Graeme Fife, 2006-2007 (Box 57, Folder 31)
  - Thomas Franklin, 2003 (Box 57, Folder 32)
  - G, 1998-2006 (Box 57, Folder 33)
    Gallagher, Gautreaux, Gilbert, Gilliland, Goldberg, Gordon, Gould, Gran, Gwin
  - Tim Gautreaux, 1999-2000 (Box 57, Folder 34)
  - Kaye Gibbons, 2003 (Box 57, Folder 35)
  - Gernert Company, 2003-2005 (Box 57, Folder 36)
  - Samantha Gillison, 1998-2004 (Box 57, Folder 37)
  - Julie Glass, 2003-2006 (Box 57, Folder 38)
  - Sue Grafton, 1997-2004 (Box 57, Folder 39)
  - Elizabeth Graver, 2000-2004 (Box 57, Folder 40)
  - Grove Press, 2002 (Box 57, Folder 41)
  - Guggenheim Foundation, 2001-2004 (Box 57, Folder 42)
  - Ha-Hi, 1996-2004 (Box 57, Folder 43)
    Haggerty, Hammond, Hall, Hank, Hannah, Hardy, Harold, Hawley, Heath, Herr, Herskovits
  - Ho-Hu, 1999-2007 (Box 57, Folder 44)
    Hofmaister, Henry Holt and Co., Hotchkiss, Holmes, Horror, Howorth, Hubbard, Hubner, Huxley, Huyler
  - David Heddendorf, 2001-2005 (Box 57, Folder 45)
  - Drue Heinz, 2001-2004 (Box 57, Folder 46)
  - Lamar Herrin, 1998-2005 (Box 57, Folder 47)
  - Brandon Hobson, 2002-2006 (Box 57, Folder 48)
  - J, 1999 (Box 57, Folder 49)
    Jones
  - Philip Jennings, 1999-2001 (Box 57, Folder 50)
  - K, 1998-2004 (Box 57, Folder 51)
    Kearney, Keller, Kenan, Kessler, Koenig, Kuhn
  - Laura Kasischke, 2003-2005 (Box 57, Folder 52)
  - Nicole Kelby, 1998-1999 (Box 57, Folder 53)
  - Nicole Kelby II, 1999 (Box 57, Folder 54)
  - Nicole Kelby III, 2000-2005 (Box 57, Folder 55)
  - Stephen King (Box 55)
  - Stephen King, 1998 (Box 57, Folder 56)
  - Stephen King II, March-April 2002 (Box 57, Folder 57)
  - Stephen King III, May 2002 (Box 57, Folder 58)
  - Stephen King IV, June-July 2002 (Box 57, Folder 59)
  - Stephen King V, August 1 (Box 57, Folder 60)
    By Diverse Hands, Red Sox Diary 2002 drafts
  - Stephen King VI, September 2002 (Box 57, Folder 61)
  - Stephen King VII, October-December 2002 (Box 57, Folder 62)
  - Stephen King VIII, January-March 2003 (Box 57, Folder 63)
  - Stephen King IX, April-June 2003 (Box 57, Folder 64)
  - Stephen King X, July-August 2003 (Box 57, Folder 65)
  - Stephen King XI, September 2003 (Box 57, Folder 66)
  - Stephen King XII, October-November 2003 (Box 57, Folder 67)
    America the Literate, a fictional essay by S. King
  - Stephen King XIII, January-April 2004 (Box 57, Folder 68)
  - Stephen King XIV, November-December 2004 (Box 57, Folder 69)
  - Stephen King I, January 2005 (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Stephen King II, February 2005 (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Stephen King III, March-April 2005 (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Stephen King IV, May-June 2005 (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Stephen King V, July-August 2005 (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Stephen King VI, September 2005 (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - Stephen King VII, October-December 2005 (Box 58, Folder 7)
    Scribner two page summary and reviews of Faithful
  - Stephen King VIII, January-April 2006 (Box 58, Folder 8)
  - Stephen King IX, May-June 2006 (Box 58, Folder 9)
  - Stephen King X, July-August 2006 (Box 58, Folder 10)
    "Poor Brit" by S. King, four pages
  - Stephen King XI, September-December 2006 (Box 58, Folder 11)
  - Stephen King XII, January-July 2007 (Box 58, Folder 12)
  - Leo, Joe King, Spring 2006 (?) (Box 58, Folder 13)
  - L, 2001-2007 (Box 58, Folder 14)
    Laurila, Draft Okajima Story June 2007; Lehane, Lendes, Lerner, Listi, Lipman, Livesey, Lynn
  - Wally Lamb, 1998-2000 (Box 58, Folder 15)
    Copies of outgoing correspondence from S. O'Nan
  - Peter Landesman, 2000-2001 (Box 58, Folder 16)
  - Ann Landsman, January 2007 (Box 58, Folder 17)
  - Jonathan Lethem I, March 2001-December 2004 (Box 58, Folder 18)
  - Jonathan Lethem II, January-October 2005 (Box 58, Folder 19)
  - Jonathan Lethem III, October-November 2005 (Box 58, Folder 20)
  - Jonathan Lethem IV, March-December 2006 (Box 58, Folder 21)
  - Ma-Mi (Box 58, Folder 22)
    Maddox, Marion, Martinez, Mason, Matthews
  - MacArthur Foundation, August 1999 (Box 58, Folder 23)
  - Michael Martone, 2005-2007 (Box 58, Folder 24)
  - Hilary Masters, 2001-2007 (Box 58, Folder 25)
  - Suzanne Matson, 2000-2001 (Box 58, Folder 26)
    Correspondence with Boston College regarding Prof. Matson's tenure
  - Elizabeth McCracken, 1999-2004 (Box 58, Folder 27)
  - Mc-Mo, 1996-2006 (Box 58, Folder 28)
    McCauley, McConkey, McDonnell, McGough, McGowan, McKean, McNally, Millhauser, Milward, Misty Valley Books, Mitchell, Mooney, Morgan
  - Rick Moody I, February 2001-July 2002 (Box 58, Folder 29)
    Draft of book review, "Shakey: Neil Young's Biography"
  - Rick Moody II, August-October 2003 (Box 58, Folder 30)
  - Rick Moody III, January-August 2004 (Box 58, Folder 31)
    Draft of "Notes in Reply to a Review of Nicholson Baker's Checkpoint"
  - Rick Moody IV, September 2004-September 2006 (Box 58, Folder 32)
  - Lorrie Moore, 1998-2002 (Box 58, Folder 33)
  - N, 1999-2002 (Box 58, Folder 34)
    Nelson, Nestor, Nogay
  - National Book Award Foundation, 2003-2005 (Box 58, Folder 35)
  - Scott Nicholson, 1990-2001 (Box 58, Folder 36)
  - Sigrid Nunez, 1998-2005 (Box 58, Folder 37)
  - O, 2001-2005 (Box 58, Folder 38)
    O'Brien, O'Connor, O'Neill, Ong uncluding O'Nan review of "Fixer Chao", Oxford
  - Joyce Carol Oates, 1998-2005 (Box 58, Folder 39)
    Regrets unable to offer quote, her policy; O'Nan nominates for Medal of Distinguished Contribution to American Letters
  - Christopher Offutt, 1997-2002 (Box 58, Folder 40)
  - Stewart O'Nan I, March-August 2001 (Box 58, Folder 41)
    Postcards from author to family during book tour
  - Stewart O'Nan II, 1999-? (Box 58, Folder 42)
    Email to Randall Kenan, handwritten notes on scraps of paper
  - O'Nan family (Box 58, Folder 43)
    Birthday cards, brief notes, family geneological tree
  - P, 1990-2003 (Box 58, Folder 44)
    Parkin, Pearlman, Philbrick, Piazza, Pickering, Ploughshares, Pollock
  - Timn Parrish, 1999-2004 (Box 58, Folder 45)
  - Pen New England, 2001-2005 (Box 58, Folder 46)
  - Lowry Pei, 1999-2003 (Box 58, Folder 47)
  - Dan Pope, 2003-2005 (Box 58, Folder 48)
  - Deidre Pope, 2001-2002 (Box 58, Folder 49)
  - R, 1999-2002 (Box 58, Folder 50)
    Remini, Ritzenthal, Rock, Rottman, Russo
  - Elwood Reid, 2002-2004 (Box 58, Folder 51)
  - Charles Nelson Reilly, 2001 (Box 58, Folder 52)
  - S, 1999-2006 (Box 58, Folder 53)
    Scott, Sealy, Shipley, Sigel Hebrew Academy, Spencer, Short, Speer, Spiotta, Steinke, Stewart, Stockton, Struchen, Steid, St. Martin's Press
  - Susan Straight I, 2004-2005 (Box 58, Folder 54)
  - Susan Straight II, 2006-2007 (Box 58, Folder 55)
  - Peter Straub, 2000-2005 (Box 58, Folder 56)
  - T, 1999-2005 (Box 58, Folder 57)
    Thompson, Thornton, Torockio, Tremblay- "Introduction/Interdiction" 2 drafts
  - U-V, 2001-2004 (Box 58, Folder 58)
    Vann, Vice
  - Luis Urrea I, 1998-1999 (Box 58, Folder 59)
  - Luis Urrea II, 2000-2001 (Box 58, Folder 60)
    11 page draft, "There is one way you could make me happy..."
  - Luis Urrea III, March-December 2001 (Box 58, Folder 61)
  - Luis Urrea IV, 2002 (Box 58, Folder 62)
    Draft "The Devil's Highway: One"
  - Luis Urrea V, 2003 (Box 58, Folder 63)
  - Luis Urrea VI, 2004-2006 (Box 58, Folder 64)
  - W, 1998-2004 (Box 58, Folder 65)
    Waldman, Walker, Weigl, Weiss, White House, Williams, Winter, Wormhole Books
  - Ashley Warlick, 2001-2006 (Box 58, Folder 66)
  - Katharine Weber, 2003-2005 (Box 58, Folder 67)
  - Theodore Weesner, 2003-2006 (Box 58, Folder 68)
  - Mark Winegardner, 1999-2004 (Box 58, Folder 69)
  - Tobias Wolfe, 1998 (Box 58, Folder 70)
  - X Y Z, 1998-2005 (Box 58, Folder 71)
    Yaddo, Yunt
  - Miscellaneous (Box 58, Folder 72)
    Notes from Debby, Anna, Lily, Chuck, and others
- Series XXIV Literary Magazines and Books with O'nan pieces
  - Colorado Review, 2001 (Box 61)
  - Rules of Thumb: 73 authors reveal their fiction writing fixations edited by Michael Martone and Susan Neville, 2006 (Box 61)
  - Century, 2000 (Box 61)
  - Glimmer Train, 2000 (Box 61)
  - Pittsburgh Love Stories, 2004 (Box 61)
  - Granta: The Best of Young American Novelists (Box 61)
  - Post Road, 2002 (Box 61)
  - We Are What We Eat: 24 Memories of Food edited by Mark Winegardner, 1998 (Box 61)
  - The Book That Changed My Life edited by J. Coady and Joy Johannessen (Box 61)
  - Ploughshares, 1999 (Box 61)
  - Epoch, 1998 (Box 61)
  - Lessons in Persuasion: Creative Nonfiction/Pittsburgh Connections, 2000 (Box 61)
  - Politically Inspired: Fiction for our time edited by Stephen Elliott (Box 62)
  - Politically Inspired review copy (Box 62)
  - The Year's Best Fantasy and Horror edited by Ellen Datlow and Terri Windling, 2001 (Box 62)
  - The Best of the Drue Heinz Literature Prize edited by John Edgar Wideman (Box 62)
  - Locus magazine, April 2003 (Box 62)
  - Nieman Reports, Spring 2002 (Box 62)
  - Montana Journalism Review, Summer 2001 (Box 62)
  - Grove Press, Atlantic Monthly Press, Winter 2001 (Box 62)
  - Fantasy Magazine, 2006 (Box 62)
  - Grove Press, Atlantic Monthly Press, Spring 2002 (Box 62)
  - Oxford American, June 2001 (Box 62)
  - Grove Press, Atlantic Monthly Press, Fall 2001 (Box 62)
  - Phantom, 2006 (Box 62)
  - Grove Press, Atlantic Monthly Press, Spring 2003 (Box 62)
SEPARATED MATERIAL
First edition signed books by Stewart O'Nan - cataloged individually in the Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections
In the Walled City, 1993
Snow Angels, 1994
The Names of the Dead, 1996
The Speed Queen, 1997
A World Away, 1998
A Good Day to Die, 1999, by James Coltrane (pen name of Stewart O'Nan)
A Prayer for the Dying, 1999
The Circus Fire, 2000
Everyday People, 2001
Wish You Were Here, 2002
The Night Country, 2003
Something Wicked,2003
Faithful, 2004
The Good Wife, 2005
Last Night at the Lobster, 2007
Poe, 2008
Songs for the Missing, 2008
Foreign language books by Stewart O'Nan - cataloged individually in the Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections
Le nom des morts, 1999
Sneeuwengelen, 2008
Un mal qui répand la terreur, 2001
Speed Queen, 1998 (in French)
Engel im Schnee, 1997
Nos Plus Beaux Souvenirs, 2001
Das Glück der Anderen, two different hardcovers, one paperback.
Abschied von Chautauqua
Sommer der Züge
Die Speed Queen
Speed Queen, 1998
The Speed Queen, 1998 (in Japanese)
Halloween, in German
Engle i sne, 1994
Das Anges dans la Neige, 1994
Śnieżne anioty, 1999
Letzte Nacht
Mi Chiamavano Speed Queen, 1999
Ortegas Finale, 2000, by James Coltrane (pen name of Stewart O'Nan), one hardcover one paperback
Eine Gute Ehefrau, 2007
Faithful, 2005, UK edition
The Night Country, 2004, UK edition
The Speed Queen, 1997, UK edition, two different paperbacks
Ganz Alltägliche Leute, 2004
Le Pays des Ténèbres, 2006
Der Zirkusbrand
Die Armee der Superhelden, 2000
Der Finger, 2003
Faithful, 2007 (in Russian)